Hello English learners, welcome
back to English pot, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're bringing
you the third part of this
series that we've created
called, "I'm sorry, I love you.
" That's right, the third part in our
story about our English pot couple.
Yeah, it's a romantic series, but
today we're bringing you an argument.
That's right.
Like in every relationship, you
have fights, you have discussions.
So we're going to teach
you how to do that in English.
That's right, in today's lesson, you'll
learn some great language that people use
when they get into an argument
with their boyfriend or girlfriends.
Right, so why don't we take
a look at vocabulary preview?
Very cabaret-y preview.
We have one phrase today.
Get a hold.
To get a hold.
To get a hold of someone means... To
try and communicate with that person.
Exactly, so to try and call that person.
For example, I can say,
"I've been calling his phone all
day, but I can't get a hold of him."
Or I could say, "Finally, Marco, I got a
hold of you. Where have you been all day?
" Exactly.
Now we're going to
listen to our dialogue, and
as always, it's going to be at a normal
pace, but you don't have to worry about it.
We'll come back and teach
you all of the important words.
Stephen, where have you been?
I've been trying to get
a hold of you for hours.
There was an emergency at work, so...
I wasn't looking for you in
the restaurant for three hours.
And you didn't even have
the decency to call me.
Do you have any idea how embarrassed I was?
Honey, I promise this won't happen again.
It's just that I... Yeah, right.
I've heard it all before.
I'm not going to take any
more of your empty promises.
This is the fifth time you
stood me up in two weeks.
You need to get your priority straight.
I'm tired of you putting
your job first all the time.
Come on, Veronica.
That's not fair.
I do care about you a lot. You know that.
I try to... You know what?
Maybe we should just take a break.
I need some time to think about
where this relationship is heading.
But, Veronica, would you listen to me?
There was a fire alarm at my
office building today, and I was...
Okay, so a little bit of
trouble in the relationship.
Yeah, that's too bad.
Yeah, well, I think she's overreacting.
You do?
We'll talk about that later on.
We saw some great words and phrases
here, so it's time for language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Today on language takeaway,
we're bringing you three words.
The first word is stood me up.
Stood me up.
The phrase stand someone up.
When do we use this?
If, for example, you have
a date and you don't go.
Okay, so let's say you and I were
supposed to have dinner together.
Right.
And you just didn't come.
And didn't call.
Right.
So I stood you up.
Yep.
Okay.
Stand someone up.
Our next word, priorities.
Priorities.
So priorities are something
that's really important in your life.
That's right.
Like family or maybe work or
making a lot of money or whatever it is.
What are your priorities in life, right?
Right.
Yep.
Okay.
And our last word for
language takeaway, heading.
Heading.
Heading is a bit of a funny verb.
So let's listen to a
couple of examples of how
it's used so we can
understand its meaning.
Example one.
I don't know where our
relationship is heading.
Example two.
Where's his bus heading?
Example three.
Where's this project heading?
So basically heading means going.
Exactly.
A heading is where you're going.
Yep.
Okay.
Easy word.
Interesting.
Okay.
So now it's time for us to listen
to the dialogue a second time.
It's going to be slower.
So now we can understand the
words that we just talked about.
[MUSIC]
Steven, where have you been?
I've been trying to get
a hold of you for hours.
I, um, there was an emergency at work, so.
I was waiting for you in the
restaurant for three hours.
And you didn't even have
the decency to call me.
Do you have any idea how embarrassed I was?
Honey, I promise this won't happen again.
It's just that I-- Yeah, right.
I've heard it all before.
I'm not going to take any
more of your empty promises.
This is the fifth time you've
stood me up in two weeks.
You need to get your priority straight.
I'm tired of you putting
your job first all the time.
Come on, Veronica.
That's not fair.
I do care about you a lot.
You know that.
I tried.
You know what?
Maybe we should just take a break.
I need some time to think about
where this relationship is heading.
But, Veronica, would you just listen to me?
There was a fire alarm at my
office building today, and I was stuck.
[MUSIC]
Okay, now we saw some
interesting phrases in dialogue.
Yeah, we saw some great phrases that
people use when they're getting in a fight.
Right.
Why don't we take a look at
some of them in Fluency Builder?
Fluency Builder.
The first phrase that I want to take a
look at today is, do you have any idea?
Do you have any idea?
This is a great way to set up an argument.
So, let's listen to some
examples of how you
would set up an
argument using this phrase.
Example one.
You forgot my birthday.
Do you have any idea how angry I am?
Example two.
Julie kissed my boyfriend.
Does she have any idea how mean that was?
Example 3. I just broke up with my boyfriend. Don't
you have any idea how sad I am. So it's a great
phrase to make that person understand that you were
really worried or really angry. Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Another second phrase that we can take a look at is I've heard
it all before. I've heard it all before. I've heard it all
before. So this is a great phrase of just saying you don't
have to give me an excuse. I know what you're going to say.
Exactly. And our last phrase today, take a
break. Take a break. Take a break. So when a
couple takes a break, they sort of stop their
relationship. Right. They're breaking up. Yeah.
But is it really like forever, like a breakup that lasts forever? Not, well, maybe it could be forever. But they're
saying let's just take some time away from each other for a couple of days or weeks. Yeah. Yeah. And see what happens.
Yes. Take a break. Take a break. Okay. So our happy couple is going to take a break. Well, I guess they're not that
happy that may be. Yeah. Okay. So let's listen to our dialogue again. And then we'll come back and talk tomorrow.
Stephen, where have you been? I've been trying to get a hold of you for hours. I,
uh, there was an emergency at work. So for you in the restaurant for three hours.
And you didn't even have the decency to call me. Do you have any idea how embarrassed
I was? Honey, I promise this won't happen again. It's just that I. Yeah. Right.
I've heard it all before. I'm not going to take any more
of your empty promises. This is the fifth time you stood
me up in two weeks. You need to get your priority straight.
I'm tired of you putting your job first all the time.
Come on, Veronica. That's not fair. I do care about
you a lot. You know that. I try to. What? Maybe
we should just take a break. I need some time to
think about where this relationship is heading.
But Veronica, would
you listen to me?
There was a fire alarm at my
office building today and I was.
So Marco, this phrase to take a break
really reminds me of a friend's episodes.
Yeah, that really famous friends episode
when Ross and Rachel were on a break.
And Ross like went with another girl. Yeah. Yeah.
And then they definitely broke up after that. Yeah.
So that's one of the key issues, right? If you're
taking a break, can you start to date someone else?
I've got to agree with Rachel. Really? Yeah.
No, you can't. You can't. So what's the
point of taking a break? Just you need some
time away. You need some time to think.
But you're not really broken up.
Exactly. Mm. That's convenient.
I don't know. They were
on a break. I agree with Ross.
Well, you would, wouldn't you? All right, guys. We're
out of time today. I hope you enjoyed our lesson
and be sure to listen next time because we will
definitely have a part four to this coming out soon. Yep.
And also come to our website at englishpot.com and leave all your questions
and comments. Yeah. Marco and I are always happy to hear from you and we
love answering your questions. Right. And maybe you can tell us what you
think happens in the fourth part. Yeah. Okay. Well, until then, it's goodbye.
Thank you.